<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<letter border="1" borderWidth="600" hideNumbers="true">

	<section type="tableText" width="600" insideBorder="true" insideQuestions="true">
		<tr><td align="center">[b]Extract from Terms of Business for Webaspire[br/][br/]</td></tr>
    </section>	

	<section type="text" insideBorder="true">1. These terms of business (‘the Terms of Business’) shall apply to all contracts undertaken by Webaspire (‘the Firm’). They are drafted in accordance with the laws of England and Wales, which laws shall apply in the event of any dispute, irrespective of the location of the other party or parties to this contract.[br/][spacer/][br/][b]Terms of Business and engagement letter to form the entire agreement between the parties[/b][br/][spacer/][br/]</section>
	<section type="multichoice" answerColor="#0000FF">
		<question>1. These terms of business (‘the Terms of Business’) shall apply to all contracts undertaken by Webaspire (‘the Firm’). They are drafted in accordance with the laws of England and Wales, which laws shall apply in the event of any dispute, irrespective of the location of the other party or parties to this contract.[br/][spacer/][br/][b]Terms of Business and engagement letter to form the entire agreement between the parties[/b]</question>
		<answer correct="true" points="2" feedback="0" afterText="true">5.  All the terms of the contract between the parties are contained in:[br/]     a.  These Terms of Business; and[br/]     b.  Any letter of engagement between the parties setting out additional terms; [br/]And for the avoidance of doubt where the terms contained in any such letter of engagement shall conflict with these Terms of Business, the letter of engagement shall take precedence.</answer>
		<answer correct="part" points="1" feedback="1" afterText="true">5.  All the terms of the contract between the parties are contained in these Terms of Business and any letter of engagement between the parties setting out additional terms. For the avoidance of doubt where the terms contained in any such letter of engagement shall conflict with these Terms of Business, the letter of engagement shall take precedence.</answer>
		<answer correct="false" points="0" feedback="2" afterText="true">5.  All the terms of the contract between the parties are contained in:[br/]     a.  These Terms of Business; and[br/]     b.  Any letter of engagement between the parties setting out additional terms.</answer>
		<feedback id="0" color="0x000000">Correct – this is the most appropriate choice as it clearly sets out what documents are to form the contract between the parties. It also makes it clear which document is to take precedence in the event of any inconsistency between the Terms of Business and the engagement letter. The latter is likely to include any particular terms that would apply to the individual matter being undertaken on behalf of the client. </feedback>
		<feedback id="1" color="0x000000">This option is partially correct. Although this is appropriate, setting the documents out in a sentence, rather than making use of bullet points, makes it slightly more difficult to read. It does, however, make it clear which document is to take precedence in the event of any inconsistency between the Terms of Business and the engagement letter. The latter is likely to include any particular terms that would apply to the individual matter being undertaken on behalf of the client.</feedback>
		<feedback id="2" color="0x000000">Incorrect – this is not appropriate. Although it clearly sets out what documents are to form the contract between the parties, it does not make it clear which document is to take precedence in the event of any inconsistency between the Terms of Business and the engagement letter. The latter is likely to include any particular terms that would apply to the individual matter being undertaken on behalf of the client.</feedback>
	</section>         
	
	<section type="text" insideBorder="true">[b][i]Payment terms[/i][/b][br/][spacer/][br/]Any invoice or other written request for payment of the Firm’s fees shall be payable within 30 days of the issue of such request. The Firm</section>
	<section type="multichoice" answerColor="#0000FF">
		<question>[b][i]Payment terms[/i][/b][br/][spacer/][br/]Any invoice or other written request for payment of the Firm’s fees shall be payable within 30 days of the issue of such request. The Firm...</question>
		<answer correct="false" points="0" feedback="0" afterText="true">shall be entitled to add interest to sums which remain unpaid□ [FONT COLOR="#000000"]and until payment is received in full, including any such interest.[/FONT][br/][spacer/]</answer>
		<answer correct="true" points="2" feedback="1" afterText="true">shall be entitled to add interest at a rate of 2% above the base rate for the time being to sums which remain unpaid after this period has expired [FONT COLOR="#000000"]and until payment is received in full, including any such interest.[/FONT][br/][spacer/]</answer>
		<answer correct="part" points="1" feedback="2" afterText="true">shall be entitled to add interest at a rate of 2% above the base rate to sums which remain unpaid after this period has expired [FONT COLOR="#000000"]and until payment is received in full, including any such interest.[/FONT][br/][spacer/]</answer>
		<feedback id="0" color="0x000000">Incorrect – this is unclear. The right to add interest is useful, but it is important to specify the rate and when it will become chargeable.</feedback>
		<feedback id="1" color="0x000000">Correct – this is the most appropriate clause. It is clear what rate of interest applies and when it applies to the unpaid sums. It also makes it clear that the rate of interest will vary as the base rate varies and is not static.</feedback>
		<feedback id="2" color="0x000000">Partially correct – this is appropriate, but it is usually regarded as good practice to make it clear that the interest rate varies with the bank rate ‘from time to time’ and is not fixed.</feedback>
	</section>  
	
		
	<section type="text" insideBorder="true">[b]Right to subcontract[/b][br/][spacer/][br/]9.□ The Firm shall have the right to delegate or subcontract any work to be undertaken on the client’s behalf. [br/]            a.  Where the work is to be undertaken by an employee of the Firm, the Firm shall not be required [br/]          [spacer/][spacer/]to consult with the client before delegating the work to any such employee. [br/]            b.   </section>
	<section type="multichoice" answerColor="#0000FF">
		<question>[b]Right to subcontract[/b][br/][spacer/][br/]9.□ The Firm shall have the right to delegate or subcontract any work to be undertaken on the client’s behalf. [br/]          [spacer/][spacer/]a.  Where the work is to be undertaken by an employee of the Firm, the Firm shall not be required to [br/]          [spacer/][spacer/]consult with the client before delegating the work to any such employee. [br/]          [spacer/][spacer/]b.  ...</question>
		<answer correct="part" points="1" feedback="0" afterText="true">Where the work to be subcontracted to a third party is to be carried out at the client’s premises,[br/]□□□□□□□□□□□□the Firm shall be required to inform the client and give them the right to object on reasonable[br/]□□□□□□□□□□□□grounds, provided always that in the event that the work is not subcontracted due to the client’s[br/]□□□□□□□□□□□□objections, the client shall be notified of any required revision to the timescale of the work.</answer>
		<answer correct="false" points="0" feedback="1" afterText="true">Where the work to be subcontracted to a third party is to be carried out at the client’s premises,[br/]□□□□□□□□□□□□the Firm shall be required to inform the client and give them the right to object, provided always[br/]□□□□□□□□□□□□that in the event that the work is not subcontracted due to the client’s objections, the client shall be[br/]□□□□□□□□□□□□notified in writing of any required revision to the timescale of the work and shall indicate acceptance[br/]□□□□□□□□□□□□of such revision by signing one copy of the notification and returning it to the Firm.</answer>
		<answer correct="true" points="2" feedback="2" afterText="true">Where the work to be subcontracted to a third party is to be carried out at the client’s premises, [br/]□□□□□□□□□□□□the Firm shall be required to inform the client and give them the right to object on reasonable[br/]□□□□□□□□□□□□grounds, provided always that in the event that the work is not subcontracted due to the client’s[br/]□□□□□□□□□□□□objections, the client shall be notified in writing of any required revision to the timescale of the work[br/]□□□□□□□□□□□□and shall indicate acceptance of such revision by signing one copy of the notification and returning[br/]□□□□□□□□□□□□it to the Firm.</answer>
		<feedback id="0" color="0x000000">This is partially correct. Although this is fairly appropriate, there are some points which are not addressed. There is no requirement for the notification to be in writing, nor for the client to agree to the revised timescale.</feedback>
		<feedback id="1" color="0x000000">Incorrect – this is not appropriate. It gives the client the right to object, but there is no requirement that the objections should be reasonable.</feedback>
		<feedback id="2" color="0x000000">Correct – this is the most appropriate choice. In the event that the client objects to the subcontractor who is actually to work at their premises, they have the right to object, but only on reasonable grounds. They are then required to address the issue of a revised timescale. The clause goes on to provided what should happen if the parties do not agree.</feedback>
	</section>     

	<section type="questiontext">[spacer/][spacer/][spacer/][spacer/][spacer/][spacer/][spacer/][spacer/][spacer/][spacer/][spacer/][spacer/]In the event of any dispute, the terms of Clause 12 of these Terms of Business shall apply.[br/]          [spacer/][spacer/]c.  In the event that the work to be subcontracted is not to be carried out at the client’s premises, the [br/]          [spacer/][spacer/]Firm shall not be required to consult with □the client before subcontracting the work, but shall at all [br/]          [spacer/][spacer/]times remain responsible for the quality and conduct of the subcontracted work.[br/]</section> 
	<section type="text" insideBorder="true">[spacer/][spacer/][spacer/][spacer/][spacer/][spacer/][spacer/][spacer/][spacer/][spacer/][spacer/][spacer/]In the event of any dispute, the terms of Clause 12 of these Terms of Business shall apply.[br/]          [spacer/][spacer/]c.  In the event that the work to be subcontracted is not to be carried out at the client’s premises, the [br/]          [spacer/][spacer/]Firm shall not be required to consult with □the client before subcontracting the work, but shall at all [br/]          [spacer/][spacer/]times remain responsible for the quality and conduct of the subcontracted work.[br/]</section> 
	
	
	<section type="text" insideBorder="true">Any code or software developed by the Firm for any client</section>
	<section type="multichoice" answerColor="#0000FF">
		<question>Any code or software developed by the Firm for any client...</question>
		<answer correct="true" points="2" feedback="0" afterText="true" omitSpace="1">and the intellectual property rights attaching to such code or software shall remain the property of the Firm. This is subject to a grant of a licence to use such software or code by the Firm to the client on such terms as the parties shall agree.[spacer/] [FONT COLOR="#000000"]The Firm shall retain the right to supply such code or software to other clients on such terms as the Firm shall in its absolute discretion determine.[/FONT][br/][spacer/]</answer>
		<answer correct="part" points="1" feedback="1" afterText="true" omitSpace="1">and the intellectual property rights attaching to such code or software shall remain the property of the Firm. This is subject to a grant of a licence to use such software or code by the Firm to the client.[spacer/] [FONT COLOR="#000000"]The Firm shall retain the right to supply such code or software to other clients on such terms as the Firm shall in its absolute discretion determine.[/FONT][br/][spacer/]</answer>
		<answer correct="false" points="0" feedback="2" afterText="true" omitSpace="1">shall remain the property of the Firm. This is subject to a grant of a licence to use such software or code by the Firm to the client on such terms as the parties shall agree.[spacer/] [FONT COLOR="#000000"]The Firm shall retain the right to supply such code or software to other clients on such terms as the Firm shall in its absolute discretion determine.[/FONT][br/][spacer/]</answer>
		<feedback id="0" color="0x000000">Correct – this is the most appropriate answer. It is clear that all intellectual property rights (which will be very valuable to the firm) remain with the firm. It should also be acceptable to the client because they are being granted a licence to use the software and the terms of that licence will be agreed between the parties.</feedback>
		<feedback id="1" color="0x000000">This is reasonably appropriate, and so this answer is partially correct. It is clear that all intellectual property rights (which will be very valuable to the firm) remain with the firm. It should also be acceptable to the client because they are being granted a licence to use the software. However, it should be clear that the terms of that licence will be agreed between the parties.</feedback>
		<feedback id="2" color="0x000000">Incorrect – this is not appropriate. It needs to be clear that all intellectual property rights (which will be very valuable to the firm) remain with the firm. The clause does, however, deal with the grant of a licence to use the software and states that the terms of that licence will be agreed between the parties.</feedback>
	</section>     

	<feedbacks>
		<feedback min="0" max="4" color="0x000000">[b]You scored [score/][/b][br/]Clear drafting which addresses your clients’ concerns is important to your success as a solicitor. Compare your choices with the suggested answer available via the link below and review the feedback you received. You should then use your reflective diary to determine what you can take forward from this exercise. You may wish to attempt the supplementary exercise before finishing this module. Click on the ‘next exercise’ button to move on.[br/]If you decide not to undertake the supplementary exercise, you have now come to the end of the [br/]exercises for Legal Writing and Drafting. If you would like further practice or revision, you can now [br/]return to any of the exercises on this topic and repeat them in any order. Alternatively, return to the [br/][a href="event:/home"a]]homepage[/a] to start exercises on other skills.</feedback>
		<feedback min="5" max="6" color="0x000000">[b]You scored [score/][/b][br/]Clear drafting which addresses your clients’ concerns is important to your success as a solicitor. Compare your choices with the suggested answer available via the link below and review the feedback you received. You should then use your reflective diary to determine what you can take forward from this exercise. Click on the ‘next exercise’ button to move on.[br/]If you decide not to undertake the supplementary exercise, you have now come to the end of the [br/]exercises for Legal Writing and Drafting. If you would like further practice or revision, you can now [br/]return to any of the exercises on this topic and repeat them in any order. Alternatively, return to the [br/][a href="event:/home"a]]homepage[/a] to start exercises on other skills.</feedback>
		<feedback min="7" max="8" color="0x000000">[b]You scored [score/][/b][br/]Excellent! Clear drafting which addresses your clients’ concerns is important to your success as a solicitor. Review the suggested answer available via the link below and your feedback. You should then use your reflective diary to determine what you can take forward from this exercise. Click on the ‘next exercise’ button to move on.[br/]If you decide not to undertake the supplementary exercise, you have now come to the end of the [br/]exercises for Legal Writing and Drafting. If you would like further practice or revision, you can now [br/]return to any of the exercises on this topic and repeat them in any order. Alternatively, return to the [br/][a href="event:/home"a]]homepage[/a] to start exercises on other skills.</feedback>
	</feedbacks>
	
</letter>